# Michael K. Brewer

http://www.iHazCo.de/ Michael.Keith.Brewer@gmail.com c:310-420-5285

I am a results oriented, self taught programmer. I have 17 years of experience in programming using 15 different languages and several major platforms. I am versatile in evaluating and using existing frameworks and libraries to deliver the applications in a timely manner.

# Experience

## **Software Developer**

Jun 2014-Oct 2014

Hudl, Athlete Experience Squad

Pivoted our desktop and mobile web applications toward a social video sharing and recruiting experience for our 2.4 million athletes, who accrue 30 million monthly visits.

- Implemented a redesign in the home page and athlete profile page to have a mobile-first responsive layout using Backbone and Marinette on the client side and a C# MVC .NET backend with RESTful components and MongoDB.
- Interviewed athletes to identify pain points which were translated to app requirements
- Used a single page JS, non-redirecting Google content experiment to learn about site usage
- Agile SDLC averaged 1~2 releases per week

## **Database Programmer**

Nov 2011-Jun 2014

UCLA Office of Compliance Services

Improved working efficiency and case tracking for a staff of over twenty health compliance auditors and the Chief Compliance Officer.

- Designed and prototyped a project management application using Node.js, Knockout.js, MongoDB, and SQL Server.
- Built an Access and SQL server solution with integrated contact management, audit tracking, and reporting for over 5000 audits per year.
- Codified and automated the legal analysis in the event of privacy breaches through an Access based reporting tool with built-in decision tree algorithm based on the compliance legal requirements. The application resulted in 30% cost reduction.
- Supported a complete overhaul of a 20 year old medical record software housing over 1 million patient records through providing detailed analysis of auditing functionality and fixing bugs.

## **Programming Consultant**

Jan 2014-Present

Sammy's Boutique (<a href="http://sammysboutique.com">http://sammysboutique.com</a>)

Launched the eCommerce fashion start-up and support ongoing maintenance.

- Launched the site on Shopify eCommerce platform.
- Customized site features including user review, recommendations, checkout flow, homepage carousel and marketing popups.

## **Programming Consultant**

Oct 2010-Oct 2011

Hamlin Emory, M.D. (http://www.dremory.com)

Modernized research data tracking and provided statistical tests for research hypothesis.

- Organized decades worth of text file and paper file medical records into an Access database
- Performed statistical hypothesis testing of physiological anomalies and treatment-response patterns for hundreds of medical metrics and dozens of therapies
- Built Excel/VBA app to automate data cluster identification

### Languages:

JavaScript, C#, VBA, HTML5, CSS3, C++ (Minimal: Java, PHP, Flash)

#### Libraries:

JQuery, Express, Underscore, Bootstrap

#### Frameworks:

BackboneJs, KnockoutJS, Total.js, .NET, Shopify (Minimal: Drupal, Wordpress, Squarespace)

#### Hosting:

Node.js, IIS, Heroku (Minimal: AWS)

## Methodologies:

OO, SOLID, Agile

#### **Graphic Design:**

Photoshop, PixIr, InDesign (Minimal: Flash, Illustrator)

#### Protocols:

REST (Minimal: SOAP)

#### Tools:

Balsamiq, Git, Sublime Text, Notepad++, XAMPP, Nodemon, VMWare, RoboMongo, Xamarin Studio, Visual Studio,

## Programmer/Analyst

Jan 2007-Nov 2011

## UCLA General Services Information Systems

Built many different applications to serve the business needs of a 1000+ staff body across 20+ departments including Fire, Police, Construction, Warehouse, Transportation, etc. My role was split 50/50 between 2nd tier help desk support and programming.

- Built a VBA app that reduced administrative errors in work tracking, saving \$40k per year in overtime costs
- Launched a materials safety database and C# MVC website to facilitate communication of safe handling of hazardous chemicals throughout the UCLA campus
- Implemented a Windows Mobile app to aid Fire Marshals in documenting fire hydrant maintenance

## Help Desk Technician

Apr 2003-Jan 2007

UCLA Facilities Management Information Systems

Role split 80/20 between help desk and programming.

- Developed an Access application for inventory management, purchasing, and rental tracking.
  Interfaced with our enterprise work order management system, time and attendance system, and purchasing system.
- Maintenance for an aging PHP and PL/SQL based billing system
- Developed a recycling pickup scheduling app in Access
- Handled over 16k customer support calls and first tier server ops tickets.

Webmaster Oct 1998-May 2001

BidAmerica

Built business tools and a website that help grow this start-up to double its gross revenue three years in a row.

- Created MS Access based tools that reduced data entry time by 90%
- Implemented an ASP website with JavaScript driven web forms
- Built and maintained IIS server

# **Education and Certifications**

- IEEE Computer Society CSDA, 2011
- Associate Degree in General Science and Computer Programming, Santa Monica College, 2015 (in progress)